Hey there. So now,
现在我们将讨论
we're going to start talking about inference and validation.
推理和验证过程
So, when you have your trained network,
训练好网络后
you typically want to use it for making predictions.
我们会用它做预测
This is called inference,
这个过程称之为推理
it's a term borrowed from statistics.
这个词来自统计学
However, neural networks have a tendency to perform too well on
但是
your training data and they aren't able to
神经网络往往在训练数据上表现太好
generalize the data that your network hasn't seen before.
以至于无法泛化到网络尚未见过的数据
This is called overfitting.
这个问题称之为过拟合
This happens because as you're training more and more and more on your training set,
当我们在训练集上训练的时间越来越长
your network starts to pick up correlations and
网络会开始发现并学习一些仅适用于该训练集的关系和规律
patterns that are in your training set but they aren't
但是这些关系和规律并不适用于泛化数据集 即
in the more general dataset of all possible handwritten digits.
包含所有其他任何手写数字的数据集
So, to test for overfitting,
要检测过拟合问题
we measure the performance of the network on data that isn't in the training set.
我们使用非训练集中的数据衡量网络的效果
This data is usually called the validation set or the test set.
这种数据通常称为验证集或测试集
So, while we measure the performance on the validation set,
在用验证集衡量效果时
we also tried to reduce overfitting through regularization such as dropout.
我们还会通过丢弃等正则化方法减少过拟合现象
So, in this notebook,
在此 notebook 中
I'll show you how we can both look at
我将演示如何查看验证集
our validation set and also use dropout to reduce overfitting.
以及如何使用丢弃减少过拟合现象
So, to get the training set for your data like from PyTorch,
要从 PyTorch 中获取训练集
then we say train equals true and for fashionMNIST.
先将 fashionMNIST 设置为 train=true
To get our test set,
要获取测试集
we're actually going to set train equals false here.
在这里设置为 train=false
Here, I'm just defining the model like we did before.
在这里像之前一样定义模型
So, the goal of validation is to measure
验证的目标是
our model's performance on data that is not part of our training set.
衡量模型在非训练集中的数据上的效果
But what we mean by performance is up to you,
效果标准由开发者来决定
up to the developer, the person who's writing the code.
即由写代码的人来决定
A lot of times, it'll just be the accuracy.
很多时候我们会使用准确率来衡量
So, like how many correct classifications did
即在所有模型预测中
our model make compared to all of the predictions?
正确预测所占的百分比
And other options for metrics are precision and recall,
其他衡量指标包括精确率和召回率
and the top five error rate.
以及 top-5 错误率
So here, I'll show you how to actually measure the accuracy on the validation set.
我将演示如何衡量在验证集上的准确率
So first, I'm going to do a forward pass that is one batch from the test set.
首先 我将对测试集中的一批数据进行前向传播
So, see in our test set we get our probabilities.
在测试集中获得概率
So, just 64 examples in a batch.
一批数据有 64 个样本
Then 10 columns like one for each of the classes.
然后是 10 列 每个类别对应一列
So, the accuracy, we want to see if our model made
准确率衡量的是
the correct prediction of the class given the image.
模型对给定图像的类别是否预测正确
The prediction we can consider it to be whichever class has the highest probability.
预测结果可以看做概率最高的类别
So, for this, we can use this top-k method on our tensors.
我们可以对张量使用 top-k 方法
This returns the k highest values.
它会返回前 k 个值
So, if we pass in one,
如果传入 1
then this is going to give us the one highest value.
那么将返回最高的值
This one highest value is the most likely class that our network is predicting.
这个最高值表示网络预测的概率最高的类别
So, for the first ten examples,
对于我获取的这批测试数据
and this batch of test data that I grabbed,
这十个样本来说
we see that the class four and class five are what are being predicted for these.
我们看到类别 4 和 5 是预测结果
So, remember that this network actually hasn't been trained yet,
注意 这个网络尚未经过训练
and so it's just making these guesses randomly because
只是随机地做出预测
it doesn't really know anything about the data yet.
因为它对数据还完全不了解
So, top-k actually returns a tuple with two tensors.
top-k 返回一个包含两个张量的元组
So, the first tensor is the actual probability values,
第一个张量是实际概率值
and the second tensor are the class indices themselves.
第二个张量是类别索引本身
So typically, we just want this top class here.
通常我们希望获得这个 top_class
So, I'm calling top-k here and I'm separating out the probabilities in the classes.
在这里调用 topk 并将概率和类别分开
So, we'll just use this top class going forward.
接下来我们将使用这个 top_class
So, now that we have the predicted classes from our network,
获得网络的预测类别后
we can compare that with the true labels.
我们可以用它与真实标签进行比较
So, we say, we can say like top class equals equals labels.
输入 top_class == labels
The only trick here is that we need to make
这里需要注意的是
sure our top class tensor and the labels tensor has the same shape.
需要确保 top_class 张量和 labels 张量形状一样
So, this equality actually operates appropriately like we expect.
这样才能进行相等性判断
So, labels from the test loader is actually a 1D tensor with 64 elements,
来自 testloader 的 labels 是一个一维张量 有 64 个元素
but top class itself is a 2D tensor, 64 by one.
但是 top_class 本身是一个二维张量 大小是 64 x 1
So here, I'm just like changing the shape of labels to match the shape of top class.
我在这里更改了 labels 的形状
This gives us this equals tensor.
使其与 top_class 的形状一样
We can actually see it looks like.
看看结果怎么样
So, it gives us a bunch of zeros and ones.
里面有大量 0 和 1
So, zeros are where they don't match,
0 表示不匹配
and then ones are where they do match.
1 表示匹配
Now, we have this tensor that's all just a bunch of zeros and ones.
这个张量由大量 0 和 1 组成
So, if we want to know the accuracy, right?
如果要计算准确率
We can just sum up all the correct things,
我们可以算出
all the correct predictions,
所有正确的预测数量之和
and then divide by the total number of predictions.
然后除以预测总数
If you're tensor is all zeros and ones,
如果张量全是 0 和 1
that's actually equivalent to taking the mean.
就相当于取均值
So for that, we can do torch.mean,
因此输入 torch.mean
but the problem is that equals is actually a byte tensor,
但问题是 equals 是字节张量
and torch.mean won't work on byte tensors.
而 torch.mean 不适用于字节张量
So, we actually need to convert equals until a float tensor.
因此我们需要将 equals 转换为浮点数张量
If we do that, then we can actually see our accuracy for
然后可以看出
this one particular batch is 15.6 percent.
这个批次的准确率是 15.6%
So, this is roughly what we expect.
在我们的预期范围内
So, our network hasn't been trained yet.
网络尚未训练
It's making pretty much random guesses.
只是随机地做出猜测
That means that we should see our accuracy be about one in ten for
因此对于任何特定图像 准确率应该约为 1/10
any particular image because it's just uniformly guessing one of the classes, okay?
即 只是均匀地猜测其中一个类别
So here, I'm going to have you actually implement this validation loop,
下面你的任务是实现这个验证循环
where you'll pass in data from
将测试集中的数据传入网络中
the test set through the network and calculate the loss and the accuracy.
并计算损失和准确率
So, one thing to note, I think I mentioned this before.
要注意的一点是
For the validation paths, we're not actually going to be doing any training.
对于验证流程 我们不进行任何训练操作
So, we don't need the gradients.
因此不需要梯度
So, you can actually speed up your code a little bit if you turn off the gradients.
如果关闭梯度的话 代码运行速度会稍微加快
So, using this context,
通过 with torch.no_grad 设置上下文
so with torch.no_grad, then you can put your validation pass in here.
将验证流程放入这个上下文里
So, for images and labels in your test loader and then do the validation pass here.
输入 for images, labels in testloader 然后在这里执行验证流程
So, I've basically built a classifier for you, set all this up.
基本就是这样
Here's the training pass, and then it's up to you to implement the validation pass,
这是训练流程 你需要实现验证流程
and then print out the accuracy.
然后输出准确率
All right. Good luck,
试试吧加油
and if you get stuck or want any help,
如果遇到问题或需要帮助
be sure to check out my solution.
请参阅我的解决方案